Now, I'll call it over to the regular scheduled meeting of the Monocity Council for Tuesday, January 17, 2023.
Number two, look for a vote or approval for the Proclamation, recognizing the Mono Elxlage, number 1320, for the outstanding community service.
So this holiday season through Thanksgiving and Christmas, the Elxlage, in my opinion, went above and beyond.
They started our community and they started the kids of our community.
I'll read a little bit here.
Through donations they received and fed 94 people with 261 food baskets.
They also had 884 local children in need that they supplied Christmas presents to.
And they didn't respond with 8 presents, they supplied them with 4 or 5 of a piece.
They allowed the parents to come in and basically do their shopping for their child.
They assisted them in that process and make sure that these kids had a good Christmas.
So we're looking for a vote to approve this Proclamation.
I'll make a motion.
Hi.
Silver.
William.
Hi.
Parker.
Look at that.
I'll take a picture.
Always.
Yep.
We got a few folks here in back.
We'll leave all your care to that back.
Woodrow.
You need in the picture.
I don't know.
Do you remember?
I can do that.
Going to look this way.
This is Mark, for each Championship, I'm over there.
I'm the exalt of your whole order of my mail,
December 13, 2020, which is basically the president of the launch.
I would like to add that, plus, out of part to play in this,
he referred several people over to this.
We see the sparklight.
They don't need over $600 from all these.
After he was actually finished doing our touries
and our Christmas baskets.
He's somebody from a toys for talks.
Got a hold of them, and they send him our way too.
And that's why we were, how many were at before we did to that?
Ah, they were right.
What?
$192?
$192, basket.
five hundred and three kids.
That's five hundred and three kids.
That's almost four hundred and
extra kids.
They got toys because he sent them to us.
We couldn't have done that.
Here's help.
And with that community advanced forward.
They supplied vehicle.
Different times.
President Biden told us to pick up toys.
And they also supplied a truck and a driver.
Dustin Foster.
They made a trailer.
So we'd go pick up the toys in a grove.
And also.
We might forget.
They also advanced also.
They donated the hundred and eight hands.
To the lodge.
So we can give up food.
And you got to let help to library help.
It was just.
It was a community effort.
So we wouldn't have to.
We're starting early this year.
So we've already started.
It's.
Now.
So.
Next.
We've.
That.
Go.
We.
That.
The top two.
Oh.
That.
It's.
I remember.
That.
Yeah.
We.
I don't have problems like that, so anyway, I just like to commend you if you want to come out and go to the outside, come join us.
You want to donate to do that too, because we need all the help we can do, we can not have done it with that to committee health necessary.
And we're starting Christmas now.
Yep.
Thank you all very much.
Thank you.
Critical job.
It's okay.
We need to go now.
We need to go.
Okay.
All right.
We'll give you a seat back.
Thank you all very much.
Thank you all.
Thank you.
Eric Wagner.
All right.
Number three.
Public input.
Let's get to personal appearances.
We have nine.
Four.
Consident agenda staff.
Our commands.
We approve.
Five and six.
So moved.
Back.
Hi.
Sandra.
Parker.
Hi.
We can come in.
Okay.
We have tonight's session.
The presentation of Audit, Audit, and annual financial statements, an independent
auditor's report from Ladana, signing.
Yes, that's correct.
Aand Madana standing.
Got one of the partners with our regional associates.
And we are your external auditors.
And so you have a couple of documents.
Good.
You.
Interesting.
Cool.
documents that I will be speaking to.
Now let me tell you first, I will speak to them very quickly, but you're more than welcome
to stop me with questions, ask questions at the end, ask me questions tomorrow or next week.
You know how to find us, so don't let me rush you too much tonight, but I also don't want
to use your time ineffectively.
So the first, I want to start with the little paper copy that's just staple together.
This is your single audit reports and the schedules that come with those.
You have a single audit report because my am a expended, more than $750,000 of federal
money in the year under audit, okay, that's what drives that.
Every city has this, you may not always have one every year, but usually you do.
So if you start with that document and you start at the very back, you're going to see
a schedule of prior year findings and you're going to see that the city of Miami did not have
any findings last year.
And then working my way from the back, because honestly, if you read this from the back, you're going
to find the things you're care about faster, so next to the last page is the schedule
of findings from the current year, and you will see that there are not any listed there either.
So what that tells you is we completed your audit, we did not cite any findings, internal control
or compliance related to financial statements or related to your major federal program, which I'll
explain in just a second, for the year ended June 32.
Backing up from there, you have some information around that schedule of findings, and
it tells you which program we audited.
When we do a single audit, we look at, and it looks like these pages are not numbered.
So let me try to figure out, you want about the third page from the back or the fifth if you're
counting both sides of the page.
We have a schedule with a bunch of numbers on it called the schedule of expenditures of federal
awards by Grant.
This is what we used to figure out a single audit.
Foundationally, this is all of the federal dollars expended by the city, and the 12 months ended
June 30 of 22.
We look at this, we do risk assessments, we look at the federal government's guidelines are around
the grants.
Several things we look at, and we determine which of these grants we are going to audit
under a single audit, and that's what's called a major program.
For you guys, for 2022, that was your Ocomo Water Resource Board money.
And that was the only major program for 2022.
Those do change from year to year, intentionally,
because we have to rotate them, but also
driven by size of other grants.
So that's the grant we looked at this year.
When you back up one page from it, you
have a three-page letter from us.
That is called the Independent Autotrist
Report on Compliance for each major program.
And on internal control over compliance
required by the uniform guidance.
That three-page letter in its entirety
relates only to the waterboard grant money.
So in it, you will see that we issue an opinion
on each major federal program.
You had one major federal program that waterboard grant.
That opinion is on compliance with the grant requirement
specific to that grant.
It is an unmodified opinion, or what
we used to call a clean opinion.
In other words, there were no findings around that.
That's the only opinion in this document.
Below that, you will see, or I guess, the page behind it,
in that same three-page letter.
You see a report on internal control over compliance.
That is a report and not an opinion.
And the difference there is that we are not
also finding that there are no internal control
weaknesses around that waterboard grant.
What we were saying is that we didn't find any internal control
So a little bit of difference in language, but it's
a report on internal control over compliance
again, as unique to your major federal program.
So that's what that letter is doing and telling you.
And then, at the front of it, who right behind the table
contents, you have the other letter from us.
We commonly refer to this as the yellow book report.
The actual title is that is the independent auditors report
on internal control over financial reporting and on compliance
and other matters based on the financial statements
performed in accordance with government auditing standards.
The fact that your government drives the issuance
of this report.
And again, I refer to it as a report.
It is not an opinion from us.
But this is where we would put any other findings related
to the city.
Findings not unique to your major federal program,
but rather findings throughout the city.
We issue a report on internal control there.
Note that that's a report on internal control over financial
reporting.
It's not all types of internal control.
But it's the ones over trying to get this document correct.
There's also a report on compliance and other matters.
Again, that's compliance with laws and regulations applicable.
two financial reporting.
So again, we're not looking at all laws and regulations.
We're looking at the ones that apply to getting accurate
financial statements.
So that is that report in a nutshell.
I don't really have much to talk to about
because there aren't any findings here.
If we had findings, we'd be here a bit longer.
But are there questions on this?
How many years have you been doing this for us?
Off the top of my head, I don't know.
I was a new partner to a two or three years ago.
We rotate the partners on it.
That's why I don't know off the top of my head.
That's guess?
You know?
Yeah.
Right.
I was thinking we had just done that, right?
We had just, yep, we had done that.
That was recent.
So maybe six or seven years.
Well, I said I was a new partner on it two years ago.
So that's why I can't answer off the top of my head.
We rotate partners.
The reason for that is to make sure fresh sets of eyes are looking at it.
You don't have the same person every time in charge of your audit.
So just kind of how we operate.
So what's the one we do with pineapple upset change them?
Jill, this would probably be a question for you then.
Have we ever had findings in these audits?
And how are they handled?
Yep.
That's what they've been to see.
I'm trying to think.
And just look at that, we didn't have one, so this is for fiscal year 2021, too.
We did not have any 2021, but for 1920, we had a finding, I can't remember what it was, but
it was procedural finding.
Oh, it was about the airport.
It was the airport time.
So we fixed it.
And they thought having finding, we say how we're going to go forward and they said.
So if you could, just in Laman's terms, explain to me the purpose of these audits.
Well, the purpose of it is to ensure that the financial statements you issue as required by
state law are accurate within a reasonable number, right?
Not accurate to the dollar, but accurate to within a number that would not change anyone's opinion
about what's going on with the city.
And that's the point.
And they're driven by state law.
And then your single audit is driven by federal law and has to do with that grant money.
Thank you.
So that's what drives them.
But yeah, if we have a finding, it's.
And back here it's detailed, like we give the cause and the criteria that you didn't meet,
the cause and the effect of that and all of that.
We recommend action, management has a place in that finding where they respond, what they plan to do.
Well, we do as we issue the finding when we're back the next year, we audit that again, specifically follow up on that finding to make sure it got cleared.
So if there was a finding in here even from the prior year, so the year ended June 30, 21, it would be on this very back page again in full detail, but with a response from us of what happened to it in the current year.
Perfect.
So we follow that all the way through to clearance and if it's not cleared, we issue it again and just keep bringing it back until it is.
As far as audited financials go, this is pretty unique.
This is I think I've been here two years now and have been able to go through this process with them a few times, which I'm very familiar.
Not with LaDonna with our legion associates who do work with the state as well, and they do it all over the state for probably hundreds and millions of dollars.
And they certainly are no stranger to findings.
And so that's why this is very unique.
I know you could probably go there right now and find other areas where there are cities that are not fairing quite so well, where they would not hesitate to present findings.
And it wouldn't necessarily be a bad thing.
I mean, I want to make sure you all understand the two that findings are all of us bad.
Some findings are not great, but a lot of times you're going to have findings and it just tells you what you're going to go focus on to do better.
And you'll have a response.
We'll track them.
We'll, you know, want to be very visible.
And it's usually procedural and something that we need to rectify.
The fact that we have none is really strange.
And I can say that the decades I've dealt with audited financials.
This is the only time I've ever had no findings.
Especially back to back to back.
So that's a good thing.
We'll take it as a win.
But what we have to resist is the urge to become complacent.
And that is the urge to say, well, everything's great.
We don't ever misstep.
We have no issues.
So let's just trap along.
And maybe we can do things faster and looser.
And I guarantee you should be in there doing findings.
So we will be, we will stay very diligent to make sure that we take this as a win.
But we do not become complacent.
And think that we can just become lacks.
It's still have this type of outcome.
Because we wouldn't.
And this is where we want to be.
So things are good.
I'm glad we're here.
We'll stay diligent and make sure that we're not having a,
a conversation in this public form that's not quite supplied.
And is this a self-imposed auditor?
Is this a required audit by law?
They required.
We wanted it.
I mean, that's.
As we show it.
I mean, we just.
I mean.
We have to make sure that we're compliant with the way that we're
expanding those funds.
So any time that we expand those funds, greater than $700,000,
within a fiscal year, we have to have a lot of improvement
that will require.
And the regards are posted online.
Yes.
I think you guys put them on the city's website, right?
We load them to the state auditor's website.
They're always there.
Once we're done, and everything's finished.
So to remember our community, we wanted to look for them.
Like a part of our website.
Or the state auditor's website goes search by Miami,
and you're going to find them for years.
They'll be the same report that we're getting.
Exactly.
Same report.
We do combine them to upload them.
So this small one gets attached to the back and the whole thing goes up.
But yes, that is what we do in both right.
If there is a finding, it's not really a gotho so much.
Hopefully it's helpful.
Something the city can address.
Unfortunately, sometimes they are worse than that.
And sometimes my job gets a lot more difficult than this.
This, this although very helpful in appropriate,
that we have ought to do 20 inches of this nature.
It's not an easy read.
But we do also have our performer that we do every year.
That Crawford, their property associate's the form source.
And that is something that's a little more understandable.
And we also publish.
But we had very good outcome on that as well as you all know.
But that was also a very good metric for us to be able to compare a year and a year.
How will it be forming?
Especially if we have things that make you sliding there or not doing so well.
We can see it.
And we should see those issues coming by at a time.
Yeah.
So as far as speaking to your financial performance,
that's more in line with what the Crawford firm does with you.
Because what I'm here to speak to is that your financial statements meet governmental accounting standards
and compliance with grants and applicable state laws.
But anyway, yes.
If we had findings, I would stand up here and read them to you.
And I told Bo that.
Fortunately, or fortunately, however you want to view that.
But that's that's what happens.
Depending on the severity of those, I will alert you ahead of time or not alert you ahead of time.
Just ends up being our professional judgment.
But at the end of the day, you would have them as with the public.
I'm sure you have situations that do not go quite as well and require you to engage law enforcement.
We do.
I shared with Bo.
I have a meeting with.
Law enforcement tomorrow about a different city in which case I have not talked to those council members yet because it's not appropriate
But I say that to say we will we will do our job and the public will have the outcome that the public has
Reason those council members are we've got a council member or two involved so that's why it's not going the direction of straight to the council
Certainly unusual but it happens so yes, you should all remain vigilant that is your job as the elected officials over the city of Miami to
As well remain vigilant with what information you're getting what you hear in the community what you hear from employees and
Reacting to it because we're out once a year you guys live here every day
So
In happier news
You had no finding so this is good. I don't have very much to say this big report is
Your audited financial statements these are if you had a for profit business. This would be your balance sheet and you're income statement
None of them are called that because we're under government all auditing or governmental accounting standards here, but
In it this is your document yet belongs to your management you outsourced to Crawford and Associates to help you prepare it
The only thing in here that belongs to our age to your auditors starts on page five
And there's another one of those three page letters from us that is your audit opinion
This is the opinion on this is not modified
Which means again we didn't put any qualifying language in there to speak to some kind of an issue with the financial statements
We found the financial statements to
Well, let me just read it to you in our opinion based on our audit and the report of the other auditors
That's because some of your component units are audited by other auditors
The financial statements referred to above present fairly in all material respects the respect of financial position of the governmental activities
Your business type activities. Thank you utility services
You're just greatly presented component units each major fund and the aggregate of everything else
So what we're saying is
These are a fair presentation of the city's financial statements
There is one thing in the report. That's a little bit unusual in that third header
It says change in accounting principle that is not typical language
But it's pointing out there was a new leasing standard how you account for leases has changed
That's a heads up to the accountants in the room that that standard got implemented
You
So, we draw attention to that, but it doesn't change the opinion on anything.
You didn't actually have an option to implement it or not, so, but it's there and it's done.
So that is what we do.
I would point out to you on your, in your financial statements, starting on page 9, you have a section
called management discussion and analysis.
It's about 10 pages long.
This is your management summarizing the financial condition of the city, and again, you use
the Crawford firm to help with this.
But it's summarized the financial condition of the city, compares it to the last couple
of years, and all written much more in layman's language, and the point of this under
governmental accounting standards is to try to put an abbreviated thing in here that's easier
for the public to read and understand what's going on.
So, I would say if you don't want to read the entire 95 pages of this report, I would
draw your attention to those 10, start there, and see if you have questions there.
I mean, financially, I summarized to your management to just real quickly summarized, essentially
the city was in the same financial position at the end of 22 as at the end of 21, which
is a good thing because you're not stockpiling resources at the same time, you're not spending
down your reserves.
So, it's a good position to be in.
And with that, I want to say we do appreciate working with the city of Miami, and we appreciate
working with your management, and overall you guys do a good job from what we see.
Any questions for the question?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Not a mate, budget amendment, number 23-12, for seating, can we?
Can we?
I think you just want to walk out with the ladies and guys that we have to do that.
We'll have to do that.
We can do that.
I'll make a motion.
We'll accept the findings.
Second.
Mark Kirk.
Aye.
So.
He stepped back.
Thank you.
Aye.
Eight.
Budget amendment.
Number 23 does 12.
Receiving and expanding emergency management insurance reimbursement
bunnies to repair damaged sirens.
Miss Jennifer Swanson.
What do you think?
I don't know how I got like that just here on town.
So I'd like to just discuss with you.
Budget amendment 23-12.
This is emergency management's requesting to use insurance reimbursement funds in the amount of 37,000.
Some hundred and thirty-two dollars in 20 cents to repair the damaged warnings.
Firens.
This is money in.
We received money in the reimbursement that we received.
From insurance.
So you've already fixed the sirens for.
Two years.
Make a motion.
We approve.
Second.
He stepped back.
Five.
Williams.
Thank you.
Nine.
The appointment of Beau Reese and Tyler Klein.
As the 2023 representatives to grant gateway board of directors for a one-year term.
Beginning February of 2023.
So moved.
Five.
Williams.
Eight.
Five.
Ten.
Joint resolution.
2023-03.
This is the good fellows on the MSUA.
We're just not going to approve it on the city side.
Motion.
Say.
And I'll add to that.
The waiver expires at the time of the building permit is issued at six months.
But if they need it longer, we can grant what extension.
Five.
Eleven.
Mayor's nomination is a re-appoint.
Megan Dory.
To the library board.
Return of the expire.
One, three.
Of.
Twenty.
212 mayor's nominations for re-appoint Debbie Pollard to the
Mime Housing Authority Board termed expire 1, 2, 26.
12.
13 mayor's nomination to appoint Corey Stots to the Mime Housing Authority termed
the term to expire one, two, two, and six.
Motion.
Okay.
Hi.
14 other new business of any of those residents
that's posting on this agenda, 15 staff reports, 16 mayor
council community and announcements.
I'm sure you're going to bring this up too, but I was at this car show
that was hastily thrown together this weekend.
And yet, it seemed like it was something that had been going on forever
because everything was smooth.
It was a great event.
A lot of people turned up, not just car people.
I mean, not just the cars, but people to look at the cars.
It was just awesome.
Food trucks showed up.
And just everybody just kind of came out.
I made the comment to one of the organizers at the casino when I worked
there.
We had an event similar to this, and it took us four months to plan it,
and they did it in a week and a half.
We probably went overboard with the four months granted,
but that's kind of how people in marketing do.
But no, it was a good time.
It was a good to see the community out.
And they had a little burnout, sash afterwards.
And that went nobody died.
So thankful.
Thank you all for that.
Not in the city limits.
Right.
It's definitely outside of the city limits.
And I didn't even know about it until I wasn't present.
But I didn't know about it until afterwards.
But anyway, great event.
Yeah.
I mean, a week and a half this guy threw all this to you.
Just together and had food tricks there.
And like a live band, like it was awesome.
Yeah.
They did.
And again, it was like it was like it went so smooth that maybe there was stuff
I didn't see that was a problem.
But I didn't see it.
So the public probably didn't see it.
It was a good time.
So I'm going to elaborate a little bit on that, because I got a phone call from Dylan Hall.
He was organizing this.
He said, hey, we're going to put this car show on.
We're going to do it that.
That's well.
I thought in place we have that you could do something like that.
But the third grounds.
And so I put him in touch with Kevin Browning and they took off from there.
But I did ask him on the phone.
I said, what do you want to do this?
He said, on the 14th of January, he said, you do understand that's a week.
to half. He said, oh yeah, he said, but I don't want to wait. I want to do it now. He said,
it's a memorial for a guy in Ken Block who I didn't know at the time. But the race car
guy, I guess, pre-famous of these kids group of idolizing. So he passed away. So he wanted
them a memorial that was pretty close to his passing. So they didn't lose the the lustre
of him passing. So Gordon Williams Jr also helped him put this on. These guys, the reason I
think the reason that went off so well is because they know everybody in that industry.
You know, they know the car guys. So they made some phone calls and they all showed up and
it was pretty cool to see our community come out for it because I saw people there that I don't
see the other events. So that told me we need to make sure our events are a little broader.
So everybody can be involved in something. But there was a lot of people out there. And
it was a nice day too for January. So a lot of people showed up. The food trucks were there.
Like I said, the band was until now. The band was there and played. And in the burnout competition,
I did stay for that. It was actually pretty cool. And it was in the county. It was across
the street in the background that Brown building that little niche there is county. So what
is county. I don't even worse. But I don't think there was any issues at all. Not that I heard
of anyway. Tireshops got some business. There was one guy that melted his tires all the way
off. He melted them all and down. So having been involved with the pretty one of these
on, I learned that these shows typically happen between April and September. And they're for
them to pull them off outside of that window is pretty amazing because most of these guys have
their cars garage didn't kept up and they don't get them out because it's winter time.
And I was told that they had 110 cars that were actually in the car show. And one guy
said he kept trying to go to our car wash and wash his car before the event. He said every time
he went, the car wash is full. Because everybody was washing there just to go out there. But
he actually mentioned me today and they're already playing in the next week. He's one good week
in before the morning weekend with what he told me. So I said go for it. I'm all in. Let's go.
So our four month planning got us 160 cars just to... for scale. So he's got to be 160 next time.
Uh, 110 was pretty good for a week and we have, and if you have a Lamborghini show, which was pretty
cool. And I got in it. I didn't know if I was going to go that out.
I did squeeze in there somehow, and that burning there, the local guy that goes and races
at Tulsa and his diesel driver Robert Robert, and he was there, and he was in the burn-out
competition, so it was neat to see everybody out, and I say it's kind of a different groove
that you don't see it throughout you know, this was a different niche of people and they were
also talking about doing a swap meat, I guess there's several towns that have the swap
meat where people bring their car parts and their cars and all that, and so they want to
do that too, so it would be great place to do, it would be kind of going to keep that,
it would keep that event center, stuff and stuff moving through it, but it was a cool event,
so I applaud those guys for pulling it off, it's such a short time, but it's fine, so it was amazing,
I don't have anything to add, just take just to address our students in the river, see if they have any
questions.
Alright, so we'll move to 18, 18, we have Mr. Richard Patterson, and he's got his government
class here from Iowa High School, and we put them on the agenda, so they can ask any questions
that they have, so does anybody have a question?
Well first I'd like to applaud you guys for not falling asleep during the whole procession, so
it's good for you on that.
If you want to ask a question, you can go to the podium there, and I said, is that what'd you
say?
I want to bring my students tonight to experience what happens in city government, Mayor Park, and
I were talking about it the other day, and I tried to stress too, and yeah, Washington, D.C.s in
the news, but what happens at the Civic Center, what happens in Oklahoma City is going to
have a lot more impact on their life, and I just wanted to kind of bring them to expose
them to this, and maybe they can be more comfortable coming to another one, or when they
see something in the newspaper, they'll say, oh, well, yeah, that's something that's going on
there, so I appreciate you generosity, let me just have an opportunity for questions, so hopefully
they've got some questions, but no guarantees.
All right, Charlie, you're first, come on, break the seal.
If you do it, then everybody else will follow, and it's a great question.
Yeah, I'll start, I'll start, I'm the Mayor, I'm around the meetings, and I got a lot of
events, I'm representing the city, a lot of decisions are made, we, we, we.
We go into executive session sometimes for some of the stuff we talk about because there's
some stuff that we can't put out publicly until we get it all down.
You know, the economic development stuff is some of that that we can't talk about in public
sometimes.
But really, the only difference between the mayor and the council, or I run weeks, other
than that, we're basically all the same, and now when I run for a reelection, I run for
the whole community about when they run, they run for each ward.
So my I'm a split up in four different wards.
So each council comes from a different ward, and then I represent the whole community.
So I'm really kind of a tiebreaker.
My vote really doesn't matter unless they tie, and then I would be the tiebreaker.
I do vote on all the stuff, but usually it's decided before I ever vote.
So one of the things I would add, just kind of importance of tonight is this agenda in
how critical this document is.
This new lady down here at the end of the table, is our city clerk, and she's responsible for making
sure that all of this information is out there, and what the importance of this is, is everything
that you're talking about has to be published ahead of time.
So every one of the community has a heads up of what they're going to discuss, what they're
going to vote on.
So if you have an opinion on that item, and they're going to vote on tearing down all the trees
and one of the parks, I would say no, but I want all those trees toward it.
That's a horrible item.
You have an opportunity to get your councilmen, your ward where you live, and say, I don't like that.
You know, enough people call and talk to them, that may influence their vote when they come up here
and they talk about it in the vote, and that's how you have a vote.
You have a voice on everything that they do, and it's because of this document.
So I encourage you, if you're ever interested in what's going on, go online and look and see
the agenda and what's going to be published and what they're going to talk about.
You can come up here and watch them do this live in action, or you can watch it online.
It's strained.
So the gentleman back here in the back says, on here, over his head there, but he's streaming
all this.
He's also recording it in the home publisher or a website.
And so you go and watch them, they're out there, and as far back as we've been recording
them, they're out there from the stroke of purposes.
And regardless of what people say, we're not paid.
And you don't pay us to do this job.
We do it because we want to, we want to help the city.
We don't want to do it because we're just here to do it to get paid.
Because we've put in a lot of hours.
There's a lot of times we've talked and so they pay me, this is a city manager, this is my job,
my full-time job.
So I'm paid to be here all day, every day.
And when I'm talking to these guys.
is they're not necessarily being paid.
When we're talking weekends at the nights,
or we're having meetings like this,
this is an extra curriculum for them.
So I certainly applaud their commitment
to this community to be here.
From multiple meetings that we have,
or other things that go on,
for lunches that have to occur, breakfast,
weekends, all of that.
It takes a lot of their time and effort,
but it obviously means a lot to the other community.
It means a lot to them when they wouldn't be doing it.
Now let's say the process is that we go through,
or sometimes kind of mundane,
appointing people to boards and positions,
that's not something we would debate,
but there's other things that we would talk about.
So Bo mentioned, if there was something
that you felt strongly about and I'm your councilman,
you come to me to tell me how you feel,
and I know that I'm gonna come up here and vote on it,
I'm going to express my opinion of what my constituents,
the people in my ward, tell me and tell me how to vote,
and that's how I should be voting,
because I'm the voice of the people,
and that's my responsibility as a council person.
You know, there's sometimes that you're facing
an uncomfortable situation here,
and I'll tell you one that I faced,
we had a guy that was wanting to put in a duplex,
and the property he was wanting to put it in on him was a zone
single family dwelling, and it needs to be changed
to multi-family, because it needs to be duplex.
And there was a lady that was upset,
because it was across the street from her house,
and she did not want us to change the zone,
because she didn't want that duplex built across from her house.
So I had to say, mom, we have to do it's best for the community,
and that was best for you.
And so I had to vote against my mom,
and do well as right for the community.
And that's my area, she yelled at me.
And we still get along fine.
She still loves me, but there's times you're going to face situations
where friends or family want you to do something
that's right for them, but it's not right for the whole community.
And you have to take that in consideration
when you're doing this, that you're going to do it's right for most.
Great question.
I'm not sure how long you're going to go now.
Any other questions?
I just want to say how lucky you guys are to have
a government teacher that you have.
We've all known Mr. Patterson for years, years, years, years.
I think I just speak for all of this.
I think you just call me very knowledgeable guy, very committed,
and you learn a lot in this class.
You live in Brad's Ward?
Yeah, I don't know.
I thought I was just trying to get votes.
You can't.
I know you're okay.
Is she?
She's in the room.
What was the name in the book?
What's your name?
Charlie.
If you can see me, I can see you.
I can't see you.
You're not going to get a picture.
I can see you.
You're right.
Got it.
Thank you.
I got one.
Tyler's pet.
I think that would have been behind it.
Knocked my name on.
Do what?
You've got one.
All right, so before we move on.
No more questions?
Last chance.
Do you look like you got a question?
Yeah.
Siff.
All right.
I appreciate you guys coming tonight.
We know this one in your school time.
So you guys had to take your own time to come.
We appreciate you coming.
You're welcome.
Maybe time.
The meetings are usually the first and third Monday of every month.
That's six caught.
After the holiday on Monday, five on Tuesday.
We did today.
It's on our website.
So if you want to look.
You can find out when you come.
But you're welcome.
I was welcome.
You can get hold of your email.
So that's a question.
Thank you.
What do you want to do?
That's your way.
Appreciate you.
Did you have any questions?
Did you have any questions before we're done?
All right.
So when we move on number 19, the German.
So a second.
Five.